<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Annu</title>
 <link href="http://annu.co/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://annu.co/"/>
 <updated>2015-06-14T10:27:46+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://annu.co</id>
 <author>
   <name>Annuai</name>
   <email>annuai.annu@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>A New Beginning</title>
   <link href="http://annu.co//blog/2015/06/13/A-New-Beginning.html"/>
   <updated>2015-06-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://annu.co/blog/2015/06/13/A-New-Beginning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/D+J+Academy+of+Design/@10.872285,77.002372,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x3ba8455085677233:0x64f2ff290d7a1ca5?hl=en&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/bH9a3FU.png&quot; style=&quot;border:5px solid #D6D6D6;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To Study Design had always been a dream to me, now that I have completed Secondary Education, it is the right time to start my Higher Education and Specialisation.Design is now a globally acknowledged subject.From the beginning of man, although unintentionally he had been using simple design techniques to simplify his tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the important invention of Wheels to the invention of  Space Ships, design had always been a very important aspect.
In the modern world thereby, Design becomes an important subject of attention.Today Computers are everywhere, and we do a lot of things using them.We use a Computer in almost every single instance of our present lives. In an ATM or a Ticket Printer to a Mobile Phone or even a Super Computer that process large amounts of Data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, from its invention to present, they’ve come a long way from Command Line to GUI and is now trying to invent the next best Interface, they are mostly not enough.Just as S.Balaram, the author of Thinking Design and Dean at my College D.J.Academy Of Design has said - even pollution and wastage of fuel are traits of the vehicle’s design, the incomplete interaction between human and Computers is also an inefficiency in GUIs Design.I would study in the coming four Academic Years, about Product Design - the way day to day products are designed and produced and I would like to specialize myself in Interaction Design - the way we interact with things, like Machines around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I have said a lot of things, unrelated to my emotions.Day After Tomorrow is my first day at College.I’m very nervous of what is life going to be like in there.I have never left my parents for more than 2 days.I’ll have to wash my clothes and Iron myself.All new to me.Also, I wish no senior makes me dance.I’m nothing more than a student at the college as of Monday.All that I know of is I’ll have to spend four years of my life in there.I’m thrilled about so many things, just like i’m afraid of many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited that I’ll learn a new language, know about a new culture and study one of my favorite subjects over time.But still, I’m worried that I don’t have much skills - I’ll have to produce them from the ground up, Teachers would be as horrible as my HSC, and much more.I can only hope it won’t be like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me just hope, people aren’t so mean to me and I have a lot of friends, even seniors.Although I won’t be the coolest, I can still be Cool Enough.&lt;br /&gt;
With Hope that I won’t Become a Laughing Stock.&lt;br /&gt;
Let it be a A New Beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Refresh to indicator-stickynotes</title>
   <link href="http://annu.co//blog/2015/06/11/Stickynotes-refreshed.html"/>
   <updated>2015-06-11T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://annu.co/blog/2015/06/11/Stickynotes-refreshed</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love good looking apps.As a budding UI designer, I should.I was a chronic user of Sticky Notes on Windows, when I had been a Windows User.Sticky Notes helped me save a lot of paper and got me to memorize my things in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I switched to Linux about a year ago, the major problem was nothing but the deficiency of apps available.Sticky Notes happened to be one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched and searched…and searched and found the only app I could use was &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/indicator-stickynotes&quot;&gt;Indicator-Stickynotes&lt;/a&gt; by Umang Varma.It is a good alternative, but still doesn’t look as good as others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just thought, why not give it a refresh, it is a good app, I can make it even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just used some free icons and font and some neat tricks to make this work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I hope this works for you too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Indicator-Stickynotes-Before&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/SIPqpgI.png&quot; title=&quot;The Old look of stickynotes&quot; width=&quot;330&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Indicator-Stickynotes-Refresh&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/fbaYkFz.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The New look of stickynotes&quot; width=&quot;330&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made a bash script, so that all you need to do is to run it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/annuai/stickynotes-refresh/archive/master.zip&quot;&gt;Download the refresh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NB:&lt;/strong&gt; You should’ve installed indicator-stickynotes from Umang Varma’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webupd8.org/2012/11/pin-notes-on-your-desktop-with.html&quot;&gt;PPA&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;       Also, Backup all your notes before proceeding, the bash file will reset all your notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Downloading, extract it to &lt;strong&gt;stickynotes-refresh-master&lt;/strong&gt; folder in home&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ~/stickynotes-refresh-master
sudo chmod +x setup.sh
./setup.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all folks!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Premam - A review by a novice</title>
   <link href="http://annu.co//blog/2015/06/03/Premam-A-review-by-a-novice.html"/>
   <updated>2015-06-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://annu.co/blog/2015/06/03/Premam-A-review-by-a-novice</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/FvgP55i.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;
The new movie in town had been hitting hundreds all week long.Premam by Alphonse Putharen is not really a one-of-a-kind movie at all.But, it still packs a whole lot of punch in the package.It has something for everyone - and that is what makes the movie a real good one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical Coming-Of-Age film with some twists and turns in the middle, that is the one-line explanation of this movie.
The plot is set around three love stories of George, played by Nivin Pauly mostly during his teenage.George falls in love with three women of different proportions - Mary, Malar and Celin and the film has a happy ending that commences in a marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot of the movie is something very similiar to the typical teenage life of a 17 year old, who gets shaped into a man in due course of time.Nivin Pauly, as usual has made his part excellent.His role as George is what shapes the whole film and Nivin gets a good applaud for his effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alphonse Putharen have introduced three new female leads for the film, who come and go out at certain places, and their excellent performances in the movie is worth mention.Sai Pallavi - one of the debutants, who plays the role of Malar, a College Lecturer in the film had an outstanding performance.Sai has shown both her Acting and Dancing skills in the film, and doesn’t look anything like a debutant at all.The hiked out role of Mary - the school girl, has only a small role to play in the film, and those Mary fans who went into the Cinema comes out as Malar fans.Celine, played by Madonna Sebastian also plays a small role, but gives the audience an excellent perfomance.The comedy in the film is also so very simple and never misleading and the movie also gets an applaud for Alphonse Putharen’s excellent writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The songs have a timely feel and the Rajesh Murugesan has done his part great with the already hit songs of the film. The cinematography by Anand C. Chandra is the next best thing to be praised for in the film.By adopting to situations, the film has a cool feel overall and gets its highs and lows all at the perfect timings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Premam is a typical entertainer, it has everything to entertain anyone for 160 minutes.Though the last half seems a bit complicated and sometimes unwanted, it still doesn’t ment the overall feel.It can also be called a comedy entertainer, mainly because most of the things in the movie ends up people laughing out loud.It is in fact, a yet another Thattathin Marayathu or Om Shanti Oshana, with a lot of goodness packed inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are one of those who want a real good movie this weekend, just go out for Premam, you’ll surely end up happy after seeing the story of George and his love’s and would want more.I’m already thinking of visiting the Movies again for a rewatch.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Last Day at ASAP</title>
   <link href="http://annu.co//blog/2015/06/02/Last-Day-At-ASAP.html"/>
   <updated>2015-06-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://annu.co/blog/2015/06/02/Last-Day-At-ASAP</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had been doing a programming course that I had enrolled for during my school days for the vacation.it had been extended a lot of times until it started on 20th of  last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a real good time for the 37 days I spent there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a short course, I have learnt a lot of things.I have new friends to call up for movies and much much more in life than it had been before.Fortuantely, i’m happy that this post ended up to be my first blog post in my personal blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript, the main lesson was what I was thought all the way along.Though I knew(sincerely) most of it, it was still interesting to learn with those awesome guys and girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mary, my teacher - weird only by her name had been the friendliest of teachers in my life.I will miss all those people from today - But as it always happens, life has to move on and it surely will.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/QO4vJtK.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; alt=&quot;Friends at ASAP&quot; title=&quot;My Buddies&quot; style=&quot;margin:20px 0;&quot; /&gt;
From left Kiran - the talkative, Adarsh - the cool one, Me, Subin - the adventurous, Down below - Aswanth - the crazy guy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
