<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Annu's Blog</title><description>Adventures of the Curious Clot</description><link>http://annu.co/blog/</link><generator>Ghost 0.7</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 20:10:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://annu.co/blog/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Does Material Design really work?</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/design"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Material Design&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the fairly new Design System introduced by Google for unification of Interface Design across their platforms. It just means that, from the date Material Design Transition is Complete, Google and Google Products will look and feel the same and unified across everywhere. You have seen Material Design&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://annu.co/blog/does-material-design-really-work/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">96915a4e-1791-48c3-ba60-5408d810b21b</guid><category>Google</category><category>Opinion</category><category>Material Design</category><dc:creator>Annuai</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 14:18:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://annu.co/blog/content/images/2016/06/Article_GV_Header-2480.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://annu.co/blog/content/images/2016/06/Article_GV_Header-2480.png" alt="Does Material Design really work?"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/design"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Material Design&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the fairly new Design System introduced by Google for unification of Interface Design across their platforms. It just means that, from the date Material Design Transition is Complete, Google and Google Products will look and feel the same and unified across everywhere. You have seen Material Design at a lot of Places already, including Android Devices, Online Products by Google and used them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q8TXgCzxEnw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Announced in 2014 with the introduction of Android Lollipop, Google has ever since been working on developing, redefining and simplifying properties of Material Design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;So, does Material Design Work?&lt;/h6&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;This is one question I always wanted to answer. The particularly new Design Language from Google for use on its products have jumped out of their own spectrum and started appearing in many Online Projects - Websites, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Material Design, a Design Language Google uses nowadays on their online as well as Mobile Products - especially Android - basically, is the kind of Design that tries to mimic paper in Software. You might not feel a connection of Mobile Phones to Paper directly, but they are trying to mimic the feel and properties of the so-called "Smart Paper" or "Quantum Paper" on Screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is a Successful Company because of their Design Language itself, I should say. Google - although it hadn't been uniform across products, had been using a very clear easy to understand and use Interaction Pattern which meant an Easier Interface for the daily user.The same can be seen in all their re-designs, though in every announcement they could use "Radical" as a keyword, it had always been the same thing wrapped in a new form, if you had the patience to observe it carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://annu.co/blog/content/images/2016/06/Google-2.png" alt="Does Material Design really work?"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is virtually no difference except for the simplification that has happened over the years, and did I tell you - the homepage of the 2016 Google is almost Material Design Certified - its hidden though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is a company known for the technological innovations they've pioneered over the very little time period which happened since the company started in 1997 as a revolutionary Web Search Engine. It was never known for any achievements in Design itself, but unlike most other Companies, had the mindset to understand the need of it and include it as it went along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google had to redesign their system to keep it going. That is where Material Design came in, from the need of a unification of Interaction Patterns to make it look similar as well as feel similar so that it can be simplified into teaching the user only a very few amount of rules to live in the Google Ecosystem. And, I believe that is what exactly they could accomplish with Material Design itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Material is different, but not better in a lot of means. It set a lot of things right, but not everything - there are drawbacks - as there are in everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, as a Developer and Designer(both beginner) am of the personal opinion that by limiting Android Applications to use only a specific set of UI elements by default, Google did restrict the Openness of Android, but that does make Android make simpler to the User.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Material Design is not that material too. Although I have read there is a lot of research done on applying the Material Design Principles as close as to reality as possible, &lt;br&gt;
e.g: The Shadows used in the Design elements are tested on real life conditions and made to match Light as it falls on the elements from different points. &lt;br&gt;
They are not so real though. The Design uses a lot of very Bright Colours and are not very pleasing to many users I know. It reminds me more of a crowded city population than the rural resident that I am. It can also be, me just stereotyping. I believe the iOS approach to Design is better than Material itself for different reasons,  personally prefer the subtleness that iOS UI uses than Android and Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From UX(not UI) point of view, material is a huge improvement from what had been Google before. It surely does help the user get things done quicker. Still, it doesn't feel very Complete though. But we can hope for improvement since the Designers have already said Material will never remain a constant, always will improve and try to be perfect as time goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I designed Material for Google(only a perspective) it would be following more of the patterns that are already there than implementing new patterns. I would've gone more into UI to make it look more realistic too, but that would end me up(I hope) in Android looking more like iOS, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It does work, only not in the way I want it to.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;  
function changeLogoToWhite(){x=document.getElementsByClassName("blog-logo");for(var i = 0; i &lt; x.length; i++){x[i].innerHTML="&lt;img src='/content/images/2016/04/text5251-white.png' alt='Annu&amp;#x27;s Blog' /&gt;";}}  
changeLogoToWhite();  
&lt;/script&gt;  

&lt;style&gt;.site-wrapper{background: url('/content/images/2016/06/pixel-material-des.png') !important;}&lt;/style&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Learning to Code: Postits - GUI App Development Story</title><description>&lt;p&gt;From my little background in Design and my knowledge of the Design Process, I knew I should go through a bit of the process for this project as well, though this mainly was a Coding Project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in Design was the question "Is it really neccessary?". It was&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://annu.co/blog/postits-gui-app-development-story/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">376882ad-78e3-4ba9-98e0-eb69ea62084d</guid><category>design</category><category>development</category><category>Code</category><category>Application</category><dc:creator>Annuai</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 05:18:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://annu.co/blog/content/images/2016/06/postits-cover-blog-1.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://annu.co/blog/content/images/2016/06/postits-cover-blog-1.png" alt="Learning to Code: Postits - GUI App Development Story"&gt;&lt;p&gt;From my little background in Design and my knowledge of the Design Process, I knew I should go through a bit of the process for this project as well, though this mainly was a Coding Project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in Design was the question "Is it really neccessary?". It was for me a necessity and that confirmed the need of the same for people across Linux'es. I had to find out where Post-its came from and why they had been invented. As it turns out from Wiki's I've learnt, Post-its were initially invented by &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Post-it_note"&gt;&lt;em&gt;3Ms Scientist Dr. Spencer Silver&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 1977 as a use for the reusable adhesive he invented accidentally at 3M. 3M marketed it and initially, though it was a failure perseverence made Post-its one of the successful paper products known to the world, nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been using Post-its everywhere all through my Design School Life, and found it very important to have one for Linux, which always was my Primary Operating System. There was a Sticky Note Application for Ubuntu Unity available called &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/indicator-stickynotes"&gt;&lt;em&gt;indicator-stickynotes&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Umang Verma&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which had too many features and made it kind of unusable to me. I respect the work that Umang has put into it, but the UI still felt cluttered. Also it was broken in GNOMEs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I had time and had to do something, this was the way to go. I learnt I should do this because no one else probably will. There are not many Umang's out there, you know. Now that I had already learnt about the past of Post-its, I knew the way to go in creating this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still had doubts on which way to go. I had options in front of me, whether to choose the easy one or the other. The options were to use &lt;a href="https://github.com/nwjs"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Node-Webkit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as my development platform, which wouldn't really need much of code and only need my HTML and JQuery skills to be implemented to it. But soon, I knew there will be drawbacks. Using a development platform like &lt;em&gt;Node-Webkit&lt;/em&gt;, its not very suited for a desktop app to serve its purpose. These HTML based applications take more time to load than normal Applications and use more memory than the native ones. I already had some information about developing GUI applications for Linux, especially the tools and Languages in use, but never knew how to use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Node-Webkit&lt;/em&gt; would just make it work, it was filled in with features, but its drawbacks in serving the purpose I required, made me step back from doing it the Node way. I decided to search for other tools and Languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python was next. Umang had used Python as the language for his project &lt;em&gt;indicator-stickynotes&lt;/em&gt;, mainly the reasons would've been Python is easy to code in, has a long lot of libraries available and would do the job pretty well. Python was the best option. Being in 25 years of existence, it was already well documented and supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn't start with Python just like that though. I learnt Python from &lt;a href="http://codecademy.com"&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt; and other tutorials at first, and wished these would help me do what I really wanted. I was good enough to complete the Python Course in an hour. But that was not the reality - I was being assisted and all I had been thought was beginner-level Programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew Gtk was my GUI tool to go with, it was the Platform used my almost all of the Applications developed for GNOME. The best thing about it was, it worked and it was filled with features, that if used properly could end you up in developing Amazing Applications in not too much Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Came a turning point, I found out a relatively newer language that was in use. It had been in development and is still in development and was called &lt;em&gt;Vala&lt;/em&gt;, Voila!&lt;br&gt;Vala had almost everything I needed for this purpose. Vala is basically a language that in the end Compiles into C Code, which is the native language used by GNOME and Linux itself. That just meant it was 10 times faster than Python(though it never mattered) and was better with Gtk, since it was written to work alongside Gtk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vala was relatively Simpler than C but tougher than Python. It was Java-ish. A week into it, I never fell in love. It was a bit too difficult for me and it was different. But Perseverence did take people to the next level, so did I.&lt;br&gt; Another Week later, I had a GUI made in a Gtk UI development tool called Glade. I could make the UI work, but didn't how to put my ideas in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A While later, I found out Vala barely had any documentation available, the website was not working Properly and StackOverflow didn't have much in there on Vala. A little more later, I started solving out the simpler problems and also found out a way to use the &lt;a href="http://valadoc.org"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Valadoc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; website, which is unusable for a common user, in its present state(try using the search option).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a while to learn Vala and for now...with a lot of not so good code, in its early development stage, it does work. The next problem did surface soon enough, How to store data! I did find a solution...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never knew how to Design Applications in the backend level, you can help me if you know, just drop me an &lt;a href="mailto:annuai.annu@gmail.com"&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;First, solve the problem. Then, write the code.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates Soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Update:  Still Alive and Kickin!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Been a long time since I wrote something. Had kept a promise to myself to not stop writing again, but had to - given the situation I was in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hard time May was, I had a lot of things planned, none of them which worked out. It was a&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://annu.co/blog/update-still-alive-and-kickin/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">4b4fc5af-053f-4b70-8c1c-6375959dfdb7</guid><category>Life</category><category>Linux</category><category>Personal</category><category>Code</category><category>updates</category><category>development</category><category>design</category><dc:creator>Annuai</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 03:44:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Been a long time since I wrote something. Had kept a promise to myself to not stop writing again, but had to - given the situation I was in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hard time May was, I had a lot of things planned, none of them which worked out. It was a plan to get into some college for a Major in Psychology, which hasn't happened yet. It was another plan to get into &lt;a href="http://geekskool.com"&gt;geekskool&lt;/a&gt; (a coding school in Bangalore), but never had the skills to. Well, it wasn't a complete turndown though - As always there is something good about everything bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been working on different personal projects in the past month - especially a Vala Gtk Coding Project. Although I boast out proud that I am a programmer for Life, I had never been. Being Frank, all I knew was HTML and CSS. Not long ago I decided I should be doing something that improved my skills in both Design and Coding fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime back, I started my own project of bringing a Post-it note application to Linux Platforms, something I loved using on Windows, but never existed on Linuxes except KDE Desktop(that too very much cluttered). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found out all Unixes are not very user-friendly, even the GUIs. The coders working behind them are backend engineers, all they would do is add a feature and add a button to it - something that annoys the daily user. There is not much research that goes into UX Design in Linux Development - After all, there is a reason why Linux'es are not very popular among daily users. When &lt;em&gt;Elementary OS&lt;/em&gt; came out, it was a bless - an Operating system that simplified almost every daily task a Windows User would perform - still in development, elementary didn't get much popularity than among the developer community. It even had a style of its own, which made the UX more uniform and simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu, the Operating System that holds around 50% of the daily-user base is the most popular Linux Operating System in use, nowadays. The kind of development going on with Canonical is very good - in fact, most of the backend code is very stable and on par with Windows Systems, might even be better - but they never cared about UI and UX, most of the Applications used are older versions from the GNOME Project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GNOME is the one thing I love in Linux'es.Though it had very humble beginnings as an App and Desktop Environment development project, it turned out to be one driver that made the best of what we see on Linux Desktops nowadays. It's not been since some very good UI designers (I won't say UX), came into action for GNOME and it's been a hundred times better since then. From saying I hate Linux GUI, I started saying GNOME is good enough nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GNOME devs had been busy developing and maintaining the Applications they already have, they might not get time enough to make new ones. I knew I had to do something to the open Source world, so I decided one day, why not fix the problem of not having a &lt;em&gt;Post-it-Notes&lt;/em&gt; GUI application for &lt;em&gt;Linux GUI&lt;/em&gt;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't have  much of a Coding background, all I know is what I learnt from the Wide World of Web. So I started researching and it went on for short streaks for 1-2 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read my &lt;a href="http://annu.co/blog/postits-gui-app-development-story"&gt;Postits in-development story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>The Phenomenon of Open Design</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Design is not very new. In fact, Design is something human beings had been doing for centennials. But as we all are, human beings are generally very selfish and always want the product of their work safe in their hands. So they invented Patents. Although patents were actually meant to&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://annu.co/blog/the-phenomenon-of-open-design/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">32b7a49c-eed2-4d4b-8f2b-d583f0b1e39b</guid><category>design</category><category>open source</category><category>freedom</category><category>open design</category><dc:creator>Annuai</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 04:48:33 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://annu.co/blog/content/images/2016/05/open-design-1.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://annu.co/blog/content/images/2016/05/open-design-1.png" alt="The Phenomenon of Open Design"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design is not very new. In fact, Design is something human beings had been doing for centennials. But as we all are, human beings are generally very selfish and always want the product of their work safe in their hands. So they invented Patents. Although patents were actually meant to be used for increasing the reach and availability of innovations, it was always used the other way round.Patents had been used to preserve and completely stop someone else from improving a product that already exists in the world, patented by someone else. &lt;br&gt;
Patents were initially introduced in 1400s and it was only meant only to preserve the ownership of an innovative product, but nowadays even million-dollar multinationals fight against each other on silly patents, sometimes even leading to patent-wars. There are a hundred flaws on a system like patenting. We all live in an open world, but we are restricted from access to content everywhere. &lt;br&gt;
I am the kind of Aaron Swartz fan who believes all the information(let it be books, videos, code) in the world should be free and accessible to everyone equally. I know that is an ideal situation, but nowadays we see people coming forward to support the war Swartz started. &lt;br&gt;
 Open Sourcing is an even newer phenomenon only decades old.First used in Software than anything else, Open Source is all about supporting the thesis of free information being available to everyone.Open Source is the kind of system where people can reuse, modify or even innovate existing systems to better heights and still be free, so that someone else can innovate it even more.Open Source recently became a phenomenon of the 21st century.While Software Companies were fighting against the idea of Open Source in the 90s, certain companies like Google understood the real potential of a system being Open and found success in developing software world uses, like Android.
Design has a very important space reserved in the future.People have already started noticing that Design is not all about how something looks, but also about its functionality.But why there are not many Design innovations there is, I believe is because of the problem that it still follows the concept of something I make should be my Intellectual Property.There is not much collaboration happening in the Design Space.If someone makes a revolutionary Iron Box...it ends there, unfortunately.This is where the real potential of Design being Open Sourced can actually help.If someone Designs a revolutionary product and makes the Design Open Source.Someone else can still use the Design and innovate it even better.The Design reffered here is not just Engineering Design or Electronics, it can always also be Aesthetical, even Graphics or Interaction. &lt;br&gt;
People and Companies have started understanding that they can’t sell their product if it doesn’t work well with the User, nowadays.The product should adapt to the user rather than vice versa.Design, in that way is getting more popular by day.Product Design and Interaction Design - though in its early stages, compared to Communication and Graphic Design have already entered the mainstream where the usability is more concerned than the way something looks. &lt;br&gt;
Open Sourcing in Design has already started in some parts of the world and I’ve already seen Design Mentors like Prof.S Balram talking about Open Design as the future than others. &lt;br&gt;
I wish All the Design Work done in this world be free and Open, so the common man can also be a designer one day. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt; &lt;br&gt;
References &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gpvcc9C8SbM"&gt;The Internets own Boy : The story of Aaron Swartz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bcXmq4yILlo"&gt;A Talk by Prof.S Balram&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Think Inside the Box!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Just an Opinion. &lt;br&gt;
We all are surrounded by people who want you to think outside the box - especially when you are in a Design College. Now that I am capable enough to think of what i am thinking, I had to find out what the phrase actually meant. I&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://annu.co/blog/think-inside-the-box/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">afc4e1e5-aaa9-4f6f-b475-47b3e89fdb64</guid><category>thoughts</category><dc:creator>Annuai</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 19:30:13 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://annu.co/blog/content/images/2016/04/9146-wallup.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://annu.co/blog/content/images/2016/04/9146-wallup.jpg" alt="Think Inside the Box!"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just an Opinion. &lt;br&gt;
We all are surrounded by people who want you to think outside the box - especially when you are in a Design College. Now that I am capable enough to think of what i am thinking, I had to find out what the phrase actually meant. I didn’t have to go through a whole Design Process to find out what that actually meant. The answer was always around me. &lt;br&gt;
What do people mean by saying ‘Think Outside the Box’? &lt;br&gt;
Well, It just means to f**k the conventions and think outwards of the Circle of Life you are in. But what exactly does it do when we think outside the Box - Nothing. You might come up with some innovative ideas if you do so, but do you actually try to implement and how many people get those ideas, not many. &lt;br&gt;
Now what I needed was to know where this was box kept and how big it was, so that I know when I am thinking outside the box. But it is all only the same thing. You use your Right brain for Creative Ideas - but those ideas are only a product of your past experiences. You have the box called Brain and you have to think outside of it. &lt;br&gt;
Unfortunately, you can’t - your brain is a hard-wired machine that can only think of what it already knows in a million probable ways. To be short - just another Super Computer(only with a million times more power and very advanced machine learning in practice - what I think it is). &lt;br&gt;
So how do people arrive at the phrase ‘Think Outside the Box’? It’s simple - It’s just a combination of basic English words that has meaning. So it’s not very difficult to create a sentence, that might even confuse people. &lt;br&gt;
But our brains are hard-wired to follow conventions - Can you imagine stuff only you can imagine. Out of 7 Billion, it is true that the idea you just had, had been in the minds of at least another hundred people. Even if you think you are a creative, all that you can do is use your skills - that you’ve developed by practice. You never will have an Original Idea, and you have to live with the fact in mind. &lt;br&gt;
Also, why do you need to think outside the box - what is the use of a new idea when there are a billion problems to be solved here in this world. Maybe that is how the world works, but that is not my point of view. New Concepts are not what we need, but new solutions - the instant ones that can sustain are what we actually need. &lt;br&gt;
We need to think inside the box, rather than trying and failing at thinking outside the box. I will tell you - not thinking at all is better than trying to Think outside the box. &lt;br&gt;
Please don’t be confused. You only need to Think inside your own Brain to understand what I just said. Your Brain is as powerful as a hundred Super Computers Combined, so you can find amazing solutions from the experiences you already have - the simple ones. Those Simple, Practical Solutions are what the world needs and not those so-called revolutionary ideas, while both does actually the same. You can at least save some time that way I hope. &lt;br&gt;
Just Start to Think Inside your own Brain, or else Don’t Think at all.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Death or Rebirth</title><description>&lt;p&gt;As always, i am in a yet another critical situation.Now that I know i’m not creative enough to imagine where Life can take me.Two days back, I decided to quit College.Just an year after my Life at DJAD, it was actually starting to get interesting.But&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://annu.co/blog/death-or-rebirth/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">3e5de6c5-5f8a-48db-8f7a-084f61717ba0</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Life</category><category>Worries</category><dc:creator>Annuai</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 05:48:19 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As always, i am in a yet another critical situation.Now that I know i’m not creative enough to imagine where Life can take me.Two days back, I decided to quit College.Just an year after my Life at DJAD, it was actually starting to get interesting.But there are also a lot of other things that happen around things.While there were certain Interesting things, there were also the opposites - I failed at completing my tasks on time and eventually faculty starts thinking of me as an arrogant, good-for-nothing student , and found myself being in a loop situation - whatever I do, I will end up taking a repeat next Academic year. &lt;br&gt;
I’ll have to spend a whole year again to learn nothing.Don’t know why, Design Colleges work like that.You can do anything you want, but if you want to learn, you probably should take your laptop to the studio, start reading and start experimenting.But I don’t see that motivation in Class.Sometimes, the subject that Interested me the most in Life, feels like its boring.I don’t want to kill myself.I believe I still have the potential, and the best thing to do to not kill myself is to leave that over-exciting and amazing place. &lt;br&gt;
I have decided to take a chance - Of all that I have read and fed myself, chances are I will fail - Not even a probability, I will - but if I have the courage to get back up and keep going, I might end up good.And that is the most worrying thing for now.I don’t know if it will be death or rebirth.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>A New Beginning</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/D+J+Academy+of+Design/@10.872285,77.002372,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x3ba8455085677233:0x64f2ff290d7a1ca5?hl=en"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/bH9a3FU.png" style="border:5px solid #D6D6D6;" width="680"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
To Study Design had always been a dream to me, now that I have completed Secondary Education, it is the right time to start my Higher Education and Specialisation.Design is now a globally acknowledged subject.From the beginning of man, although unintentionally he had been using simple design techniques&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://annu.co/blog/a-new-beginning/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">0ad46b09-3b1d-49fd-840a-811be3015497</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Life</category><category>College</category><dc:creator>Annuai</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 15:44:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/D+J+Academy+of+Design/@10.872285,77.002372,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x3ba8455085677233:0x64f2ff290d7a1ca5?hl=en"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/bH9a3FU.png" style="border:5px solid #D6D6D6;" width="680"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
To Study Design had always been a dream to me, now that I have completed Secondary Education, it is the right time to start my Higher Education and Specialisation.Design is now a globally acknowledged subject.From the beginning of man, although unintentionally he had been using simple design techniques to simplify his tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the important invention of Wheels to the invention of  Space Ships, design had always been a very important aspect. &lt;br&gt;
In the modern world thereby, Design becomes an important subject of attention.Today Computers are everywhere, and we do a lot of things using them.We use a Computer in almost every single instance of our present lives. In an ATM or a Ticket Printer to a Mobile Phone or even a Super Computer that process large amounts of Data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, from its invention to present, they've come a long way from Command Line to GUI and is now trying to invent the next best Interface, they are mostly not enough.Just as S.Balaram, the author of Thinking Design and Dean at my College D.J.Academy Of Design has said - even pollution and wastage of fuel are traits of the vehicle's design, the incomplete interaction between human and Computers is also an inefficiency in GUIs Design.I would study in the coming four Academic Years, about Product Design - the way day to day products are designed and produced and I would like to specialize myself in Interaction Design - the way we interact with things, like Machines around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I have said a lot of things, unrelated to my emotions.Day After Tomorrow is my first day at College.I'm very nervous of what is life going to be like in there.I have never left my parents for more than 2 days.I'll have to wash my clothes and Iron myself.All new to me.Also, I wish no senior makes me dance.I'm nothing more than a student at the college as of Monday.All that I know of is I'll have to spend four years of my life in there.I'm thrilled about so many things, just like i'm afraid of many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm excited that I'll learn a new language, know about a new culture and study one of my favorite subjects over time.But still, I'm worried that I don't have much skills - I'll have to produce them from the ground up, Teachers would be as horrible as my HSC, and much more.I can only hope it won't be like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me just hope, people aren't so mean to me and I have a lot of friends, even seniors.Although I won't be the coolest, I can still be Cool Enough.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
With Hope that I won't Become a Laughing Stock.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Let it be a A New Beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>A Refresh to indicator-stickynotes</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I love good looking apps. As a budding UI designer, I should. I was a chronic user of Sticky Notes on Windows, when I had been a Windows User. Sticky Notes helped me save a lot of paper and got me to memorize my things in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I switched&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://annu.co/blog/a-refresh-to-indicator-stickynotes/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">fcacb113-8a48-459e-ae59-d3ecf74f380a</guid><category>Code</category><category>Linux</category><category>Application</category><category>Hack</category><dc:creator>Annuai</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 06:16:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I love good looking apps. As a budding UI designer, I should. I was a chronic user of Sticky Notes on Windows, when I had been a Windows User. Sticky Notes helped me save a lot of paper and got me to memorize my things in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I switched to Linux about a year ago, the major problem was nothing but the deficiency of apps available. Sticky Notes happened to be one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched and searched...and searched and found the only app I could use was &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/indicator-stickynotes"&gt;Indicator-Stickynotes&lt;/a&gt; by Umang Varma. It is a good alternative, but still doesn't look as good as others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just thought, why not give it a refresh, it is a good app, I can make it even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just used some free icons and font and some neat tricks to make this work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I hope this works for you too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Indicator-Stickynotes-Before" src="http://i.imgur.com/1iagaSE.jpg" title="The Old vs New Look"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made a bash script, so that all you need to do is to run it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/annuai/stickynotes-refresh/archive/master.zip"&gt;Download the refresh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NB:&lt;/strong&gt; You should've installed indicator-stickynotes from Umang Varma's &lt;a href="http://www.webupd8.org/2012/11/pin-notes-on-your-desktop-with.html"&gt;PPA&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Also, Backup all your notes before proceeding, the bash file will reset all your notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Downloading, extract it to &lt;strong&gt;stickynotes-refresh-master&lt;/strong&gt; folder in home&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ~/stickynotes-refresh-master
sudo chmod +x setup.sh
./setup.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's all folks!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Premam - A review by a novice</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The new movie in town had been hitting hundreds all week long.Premam by Alphonse Putharen is not really a one-of-a-kind movie at all.But, it still packs a whole lot of punch in the package.It has something for everyone - and that is what makes the movie a&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://annu.co/blog/premam-a-review-by-a-novice/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">f69f05ac-f108-4ced-ad20-a50933cc3e0e</guid><category>Film</category><category>Review</category><category>Premam</category><dc:creator>Annuai</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 15:11:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://annu.co/blog/content/images/2016/04/premam_malayalam-movie-cinema-daddy-1.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://annu.co/blog/content/images/2016/04/premam_malayalam-movie-cinema-daddy-1.jpg" alt="Premam - A review by a novice"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new movie in town had been hitting hundreds all week long.Premam by Alphonse Putharen is not really a one-of-a-kind movie at all.But, it still packs a whole lot of punch in the package.It has something for everyone - and that is what makes the movie a real good one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical Coming-Of-Age film with some twists and turns in the middle, that is the one-line explanation of this movie. &lt;br&gt;
The plot is set around three love stories of George, played by Nivin Pauly mostly during his teenage.George falls in love with three women of different proportions - Mary, Malar and Celin and the film has a happy ending that commences in a marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot of the movie is something very similiar to the typical teenage life of a 17 year old, who gets shaped into a man in due course of time.Nivin Pauly, as usual has made his part excellent.His role as George is what shapes the whole film and Nivin gets a good applaud for his effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alphonse Putharen have introduced three new female leads for the film, who come and go out at certain places, and their excellent performances in the movie is worth mention.Sai Pallavi - one of the debutants, who plays the role of Malar, a College Lecturer in the film had an outstanding performance.Sai has shown both her Acting and Dancing skills in the film, and doesn’t look anything like a debutant at all.The hiked out role of Mary - the school girl, has only a small role to play in the film, and those Mary fans who went into the Cinema comes out as Malar fans.Celine, played by Madonna Sebastian also plays a small role, but gives the audience an excellent perfomance.The comedy in the film is also so very simple and never misleading and the movie also gets an applaud for Alphonse Putharen’s excellent writing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The songs have a timely feel and the Rajesh Murugesan has done his part great with the already hit songs of the film. The cinematography by Anand C. Chandra is the next best thing to be praised for in the film.By adopting to situations, the film has a cool feel overall and gets its highs and lows all at the perfect timings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Premam is a typical entertainer, it has everything to entertain anyone for 160 minutes.Though the last half seems a bit complicated and sometimes unwanted, it still doesn’t ment the overall feel.It can also be called a comedy entertainer, mainly because most of the things in the movie ends up people laughing out loud.It is in fact, a yet another Thattathin Marayathu or Om Shanti Oshana, with a lot of goodness packed inside.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are one of those who want a real good movie this weekend, just go out for Premam, you’ll surely end up happy after seeing the story of George and his love’s and would want more.I’m already thinking of visiting the Movies again for a rewatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to mention - I don't have any right to criticize a film that is born with the hard work of a lot of people - this was just my opinion, which I just wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Last Day at ASAP</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I had been doing a programming course that I had enrolled for during my school days for the vacation.it had been extended a lot of times until it started on 20th of  last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a real good time for the 37 days I spent there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://annu.co/blog/last-day-at-asap/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b303a7c-5e57-4b85-8c73-64d136b3e395</guid><category>Friends</category><category>ASAP</category><category>Coding</category><dc:creator>Annuai</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 10:05:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I had been doing a programming course that I had enrolled for during my school days for the vacation.it had been extended a lot of times until it started on 20th of  last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a real good time for the 37 days I spent there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a short course, I have learnt a lot of things.I have new friends to call up for movies and much much more in life than it had been before.Fortuantely, i’m happy that this post ended up to be my first blog post in my personal blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript, the main lesson was what I was thought all the way along.Though I knew(sincerely) most of it, it was still interesting to learn with those awesome guys and girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mary, my teacher - weird only by her name had been the friendliest of teachers in my life.I will miss all those people from today - But as it always happens, life has to move on and it surely will. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/QO4vJtK.jpg" width="700" alt="Friends at ASAP" title="My Buddies" style="margin:20px 0;"&gt; &lt;br&gt;
From left Kiran - the talkative, Adarsh - the cool one, Me, Subin - the adventurous, Down below - Aswanth - the crazy guy!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>